Guide to the Time Inc. Life Editorial Records 1937-2013 MS 3009-RG 9
New-York Historical Society
- Series II.C. Managing Editor Judith Daniels Files, 1982-1987; 231771; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  - Stringers: Time-Life News Service, 1982; 232524 (Offsite-box 2208, Folder 33)
- Series II.D. Managing Editor Patricia Ryan Files, 1987-1989; 231772; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  According to a memoranda in the Judith Daniels Files, Patricia Ryan was named Life Managing Editor in April 1987. Prior she was Managing Editor of People from 1982 to 1987, the second to hold this position, and the first woman at Time Inc. in an top editorial position.
  Weber, Bruce. "Patricia Ryan, a Managing Editor at Time Inc., Dies at 75." The New York Times, December 31, 2013. https://www.nytimes.com/2014/01/01/business/media/patricia-ryan-75-an-editor-at-time-inc-dies.html.
  Folder titles are a mix of article topics, writer names, professional organizations, and names of other editorial professionals. Records include responses to letters from readers; reader complaints (Bra Cover); correspondence with subjects or sources of articles, freelance writers, current and former Time Inc. staff, and editors at other publications; requests to possible subjects of stories; article proposals; article drafts; corrections from the subjects of articles (Cartier-Bresson); and memoranda assigning tasks on articles. Correspondence from notable people is frequently present as photocopies (Cartier-Bresson, Mario Cuomo); it isn't know where the originals are located.
  - Aids in Haiti, 1987; 232596 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 1)
  - Adams, Susan, 1988; 232597 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 2)
  - American Dream, 1989; 232598 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 3)
  - American Society of Magazine Editors, 1989; 232599 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 4-5)
  - Andersen, Christopher, 1987-1988; 232601 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 6)
  - Bakker, Jim, 1987; 232602 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 7)
  - Bell, Charles, 1987; 232603 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 8)
  - Benigno, Teodoro (Philippines President's Press Secretary), 1989; 232604 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 9)
  - Bra Cover, 1989; 232605 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 10)
  - Brandy, Leo, undated; 232606 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 11)
  - Carier-Bresson, Henri, 1987; 232608 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 12)
  - Cava, Marco della, 1988; 232610 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 13)
  - Civil Rights Issue, 1987-1988; 232611 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 14)
  - Clarkson, Rich, 1987; 232612 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 15)
  - Constitution Issue, 1988; 232613 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 16)
  - Copage, Eric, 1988; 232615 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 17)
  - Creamer, Robert, 1989; 232616 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 18)
  - Cuomo, Mario, 1987; 232617 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 19)
  - Curtis Brown Ltd, 1988; 232618 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 20)
  - Cutest Baby in American Contest, 1989; 232619 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 21)
  - Daugherty, Jennifer, 1988; 232620 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 22)
  - Destito, John, 1987; 232621 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 23)
  - Driscoll, Dennis, 1989; 232624 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 24)
  - Durrell, Richard, 1988; 232625 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 25)
  - Easton, Yvonne, 1989; 232626 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 26)
  - Edenfield, Thomas Keen, 1987; 232627 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 27)
  - Edison, Thomas, 1988; 232628 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 28)
  - Elliot, Alexander, 1988; 232629 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 29)
  - Fayard, Judy, 1987; 232630 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 30)
  - Feifer, George, 1987; 232631 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 31)
  - Ferraro, Geraldine, 1988; 232632 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 32)
  - Fitzwater, Marlin, 1989; 232633 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 33)
  - Freeman, Steve, 1989; 232634 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 34)
  - Friedan, Betty, 1987; 232635 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 35)
  - Gordon, Nicholas, 1988; 232636 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 36)
  - Graham, Alexandra, 1989; 232637 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 37)
  - Graves, Ralph, 1988; 232638 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 38)
  - Greely, William, 1988; 232639 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 39)
  - Griscom, Thomas, 1988; 232640 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 40)
  - Hanley, John, 1988; 232641 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 41)
  - Havemann, Ernest, 1987; 232643 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 42)
  - Hollywood Issue, 1988; 232645 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 43)
  - Ikematsu, Toshio, 1987; 232646 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 44)
  - Keller, Helen: Photograph License, undated; 232647 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 45)
  - Kennedy, Ethel, 1987; 232649 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 46)
  - Kensington Palace, 1987; 232650 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 47)
    Includes correspondence from a Lady in Waiting.
  - Knauth, Percy, 1988; 232651 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 48)
  - Knebel, Fletcher, 1987; 232652 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 49)
  - Koch, Ed, 1988; 232653 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 50)
    Includes original correspondence.
  - Life Weekly, 1988-1989; 232657 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 54-58)
    Includes article ideas, a study on what Life subscribers read, and records on the development of Picture Weekly.
  - Kravis, Henry, 1988; 232654 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 51)
  - Kunhardt Productions, 1989; 232655 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 52)
  - Les, Jackie, 1989; 232656 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 53)
  - Little, Brown and Company, 1988; 232658 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 59)
  - Luce, Hank, 1988; 232659 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 60)
  - Lyle, Robert, 1988; 232660 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 61)
  - Mano, Keith, undated; 232661 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 62)
  - March of Dimes, 1989; 232662 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 63)
  - Miller, Arthur, 1987; 232663 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 64)
  - Moores, Alan, 1988; 232664 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 65)
  - Neary, John, 1988-1989; 232700 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 66)
  - Neuhaus, Cable, 1988; 232702 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 67)
  - Nicholas, Nick, 1988; 232703 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 68)
  - Nicholas, Nick, 1988; 232704 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 68)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1987-1989; 232705 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 69)
  - O'Keefe, John, 1988; 232706 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 70)
  - Oxmoor House, 1988; 232707 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 71)
  - Penberthy, Jeff, 1988; 232708 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 72)
  - Photo Contest, 1987; 232709 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 73)
  - Potenberg, Jamie, 1988; 232710 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 74)
  - Presidents Issue, 1987; 232711 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 75)
  - The Presidents: The White House, 1987; 232712 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 76)
    Includes copies of Henry Grunwald's letter to the White House.
  - Profects (Camelot Outline), 1987; 232713 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 77)
  - Rasuli, Hojatoleslam, 1989; 232714 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 78)
  - Readers' Response, 1987-1989; 232716 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 79)
  - Reed, Lou, 1989; 232717 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 80)
  - Roddy, Joseph, 1988; 232718 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 81)
  - Rosenblatt, Robert, 1989; 232719 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 82)
  - Rushdie, Salman, 1989; 232720 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 83)
  - Russian Correspondence, 1987-1989; 232721 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 84)
  - Rybakov, Anatoly: Book, 1986; 232723 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 85)
  - Savarese, Carolyn, 1989; 232724 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 86)
  - Shapiro, Jim, 1988; 232725 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 87)
  - Small, Michael, 1989; 232726 (Offsite-box 2209, Folder 88)
  - Soviet Union Meeting, 1989; 232765 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 1)
    Includes discussion of Christopher Meigher's proposal on sale of publications in the Soviet Union.
  - Speeches: Food Marketing Institute, 1983; 232767 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 2)
  - Speeches: Social Change/Trends, 1987; 232768 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 3)
  - Staff Announcements, 1987-1989; 232769 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 4)
  - Story Suggestions: Rejects, 1987-1989; 232770 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 5-10)
  - Strauss, Roger, 1987; 232771 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 11)
  - Strongin, James, 1987; 232772 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 12)
  - Symposium, 1988; 232773 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 13)
  - Talbott, Strobe, 1989; 232774 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 14)
  - Thompson, Edward, 1988-1989; 232775 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 15)
    Managing Editor of Life in 1949. Includes correspondence during his role as a consultant for Life.
  - Trends, 1986; 232777 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 16)
  - Twentieth Anniversary Space Landing, 1989; 232778 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 17)
  - Twentieth Century, 1988; 232780 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 18)
  - Voboril, Mary, 1987-1989; 232781 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 19)
  - Waite, Terence, 1987; 232782 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 20)
  - William Morris Agency, 1989; 232783 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 21)
  - Williams, Margaret, 1988; 232785 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 22)
  - Wilson, Deidre, 1988; 232786 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 23)
  - Winerip, Mike, 1988; 232787 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 24)
  - Wood, Roger, 1989; 232788 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 25)
  - World Hunger Year, 1989; 232789 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 26)
  - Your Best War Story, 1989; 232790 (Offsite-box 2210, Folder 27)
- Series II.E. Managing Editor Daniel Okrent Files, 1992-1996; 232800; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  After serving as Assistant Managing Editor, Daniel Okrent was promoted to Managing Editor for Life in December 1992 and served in this position until 1996. At that time, he was appointed as an editor for New Media, Time Inc.'s internet media umbrella.
  Records includes correspondence and memorada to and from Daniel Okrent while he was the Assistant Manging Editor and Managing Editor for Life. Included are letters from readers and other publications' editors and writers; article proposals; and some Time Inc. interdepartmental correspondence. Some of his records as Life Managing Editor are intermingled with his files in the New Media record group.
  Organized chronologically, then alphabetically.
  - Annual Bonuses [RESTRICTED], 1992 (Offsite-box R38)
  - Annual Incentive Program Goals, 1990-1996; 232805 (Offsite-box 2211, Folder 1)
  - Annual Incentive Program Goals [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R38)
  - Bolotin, Susan, 1992-1996; 232806 (Offsite-box 2211, Folder 2)
  - Bolotin, Susan [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R38)
  - Correspondence: 1992-1993, 232807 (Offsite-box 2211, Folder 3-14)
  - Correspondence: 1994, 232811 (Offsite-box 2212, Folder 1-4)
  - Memoranda, 1994; 232812 (Offsite-box 2212, Folder 5)
  - Chron File: May-November, 1995; 232813 (Offsite-box 2212, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1995-1996, 232814 (Offsite-box 2212, Folder 7-15)
- Series II.F. Managing Editor General Files, 1978-1992, 2002; 231773; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  The majority of this material is from Life Managing Editor (ME) Jim Gaines, who began in this role in 1989 after serving as People ME. Other MEs represented in the materials are Judy Daniels and Richard Stolley, who succeeded Philip Kunhardt briefly before Daniels. A container list accompanied the files stating that the materials were sent to the archives by Life Chief of Research June Goldberg, but not that they are her files.
  Several files refer to Life Weekly, which is a new iteration of Life intended to be different from both the original and the revived monthly. The 1990 presentation from Gaines describes it.
  Some folders have People magazine materials, possibly carried over by Gaines.
  Organized alphabetically with forms transferring the material to the Time Inc. Archives at the front.
  - Transfer Forms, 2002; 232874 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 1)
  - Bonniwell, Kate: Memoranda, 1992; 232875 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 2)
  - Book Proposals, 1988-1989; 232876 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 3)
  - Brewster, Dan: General, 1992; 232878 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 4)
  - Brewster, Dan: Life Weekly Update, 1992; 232879 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 5)
  - Brooks, Garth, 1992; 232881 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 6)
  - Concept Study, 1988; 232882 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 7)
  - Conflict of Interest, 1982-1992; 232883 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 8)
  - Consumer Marketing Report, 1990; 232884 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 9)
  - Consumer Study, 1989; 232885 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 10)
  - Disney, 1992; 232886 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 11)
  - Documentaries, 1986; 232898 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 12)
  - Elliman, Don and Christopher Meigher: Memoranda, 1992; 232902 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 13)
  - Eyes Prospectus, 1992; 232904 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 14)
  - Focus Groups, 1989-1992; 232906 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 15-16)
  - Freelancers: Independent Contractor Status Memorandum, 1987; 232908 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 17)
  - Freelancers: Independent Contractor Status Memorandum [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R38)
  - Kanuit, Cathy: Memoranda, 1992; 232909 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 18)
  - Kodak Photo-CD Release: John Papanek, 1992; 232910 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 19)
  - Lawsuit "Life" [RESTRICTED], 1988-1989 (Offsite-box R38)
  - Legal [RESTRICTED], 1992 (Offsite-box R38)
  - Licensing, 1983-1986; 232912 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 20)
  - Life as a Biweekly: Memoranda, 1988; 232913 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 21)
  - Life Español, 1990; 232916 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 22)
  - Life Japan, 1990; 232917 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 23-24)
  - "Life: Living Legends", 1991; 232926 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 25)
  - Life Television Show (Harry Moses), 1989; 232920 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 26)
  - Life Weekly: "Fast Grown" Scenario, 1992; 232922 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 27)
  - Life Weekly: Presentation, 1990; 232923 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 28)
  - Life Weekly: Test Results, 1991; 232924 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 29)
  - Line Extension Projects, 1992; 232927 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 30)
  - Logos, 1990; 232929 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 31)
  - Magazines and Television, 1983; 232930 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 32)
  - Magazine Group: Publishers' Conference, 1988; 232931 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 33)
  - Meigher, Christopher: Memoranda, 1992; 232932 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 34)
  - Memoranda to Staff (from Life and Corporate), 1990-1992; 232933 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 35)
  - Messner, Vetere, Berger, Carey, Schmetterer (Ad agency), 1989-1992; 232935 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 36-37)
  - New Subscriber Survey, 1991; 232936 (Offsite-box 2213, Folder 38)
  - Operating Review, 1987-1990; 232939 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 1-3)
  - People/Life Ad Sales Memoranda, 1992; 232940 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 4)
  - People: Baby Boomers' Guide, 1985; 232941 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 5)
  - Proctor and Gamble/Time Warner: "Your Family Matters", 1992; 232942 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 6)
  - Publicity Memoranda, 1992; 232943 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 7)
  - Publishing Staff Memoranda, 1989-1992; 232944 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 8)
  - Quality Initiative Memorandum from Don Barr, 1992; 232945 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 9)
  - Research Report: New Life Perspectives, 1989; 232946 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 10)
  - Research Review, 1988-1992; 232947 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 11-12)
  - Sawyer Miller Group Study, 1989; 232948 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 13)
  - Simpson, Cleary, 1992; 232949 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 14-15)
  - SMRB, 1990; 232950 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 16)
  - Staff Lists, 1984-1986; 232951 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 17)
  - Subsidiary Rights Policy, 1991; 232952 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 18)
  - Syndication Policy, 1978-1985; 232953 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 19)
  - Television and Film Rights: Jason McManus Memorandum, 1991; 232954 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 20)
  - United Nations Somalia Exhibit, 1992; 232955 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 21)
  - Video Concepts, 1990; 232956 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 22)
  - Wong, Derrick and Roger Neal: Francise Development, 1992; 232957 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 23)
  - Wong, Derrick: Foreign Translation, 1989-1992; 232958 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 24)
- Series III. Executive Editor Eleanor Graves Files, 1978-1982; 231774; 0.5 Linear feet in 6 folders
  After holding several other positions at Time Inc. including associate editor for the original Life, Eleanor Graves was named Assistant Managing Editor of the revived Life in 1978. In 1981, she was promoted to Executive Editor.
  Eleanor Graves's files contain her business correspondence and files on three Life staff. Correspondence includes letter from readers, interoffice memoranda, and story suggestions. Staff files are primiarly correspondence on work issues.
  - Business Correspondence, 1982; 232959 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 25-26)
  - Fentress, Cal [RESTRICTED], 1982 (Offsite-box R38)
  - Glatzer, Paula (Copy Desk), 1978-1982; 232960 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 27)
  - Kunhardt, Philip, 1979-1982; 232961 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 28)
  - Larsen, Jonathan: Letter Agreements [RESTRICTED], 1981-1982 (Offsite-box R38)
  - Loengard, John: Photography, 1981-1982; 232962 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 29)
- Series IV.A. Senior Editor Gene Farmer Files, 1958-1972, 2005-2006; 10 Linear feet in 10 record cartons
  Biographical / Historical
  Gene Farmer started at Life as a sports editor. He then held positions as assistant national affairs editor, the London bureau chief, and the New York-based foreign editor. After working on installations of Douglas MacArthur's memoirs, he was made responsible for excerpting other works for publication in Life. He published two books: Massachusetts: Anatomy of Excellence and First on the Moon: A Voyage with Neil Armstrong, Michael Collins and Edwin E. Aldrin, Jr.. He died in 1972 while still employed by Life.
  Gene Farmer, a Senior Editor Of Life Magazine, Dead at 52. New York Times, June 22, 1972.
  Gene Farmer's files include general material sent to the Time Inc. Archives by his wife after his death and his office files created while writing the book First on the Moon.
  Organized into two subseries:
  Subseries IV.A.1. General Files
  Subseries IV.A.2. First on the Moon: A Voyage with Neil Armstrong, Michael Collins and Edwin E. Aldrin, Jr. Files
  - Subseries IV.A.1. General Files, 1958-1972, 2006; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    General Files contain material sent to the Time Inc. Archives by Farmer's wife Enid in 2006. The majority are work files that may have been at home upon his death along with one file with materials collected about his death.
    Files maintain the order designated by the included list with transfer correspondence and materials at the front.
    - Enid Farmer Correspondence to Archives, 2006 (Offsite-box 2301, Folder 1)
    - List of Files sent by Enid Farmer?, 2006? (Offsite-box 2301, Folder 2)
      It is unclear if this list was written by Enid Farmer or by the Time Inc. Archives.
    - Family Papers Tag, undated (Offsite-box 2301, Folder 3)
      This tag was attached to an empty paper bag. The contents listed were not present with this box of materials.
    - Speeches, 1959-1971 (Offsite-box 2301, Folder 4)
    - First on the Moon: Reviews and Letters, 1970 (Offsite-box 2301, Folder 5-7)
    - Death, 1972 (Offsite-box 2301, Folder 8)
      Materials were collected after Farmer's death and include his obituary, some personal items, correspondence from friends and family, Enid Farmer's response (open letter?) to correspondence she received upon his death, photographic negatives of the funeral, and Dora Jane Hamblin's draft rememberance article.
    - MacArthur, Douglas: Manuscript and Reader Poems, 1963-1971 (Offsite-box 2301, Folder 9-11)
    - Galindez Affair, 1958 (Offsite-box 2301, Folder 12-13)
      Includes some correspondence and research material related to this article.
    - Travel Articles and Reports, 1959-1969 (Offsite-box 2301, Folder 14-15)
  - Subseries IV.A.2. First on the Moon: A Voyage with Neil Armstrong, Michael Collins and Edwin E. Aldrin, Jr. Files, 1963-1971, 2005; 230644; 9 Linear feet in 9 record cartons
    Life Senior Editor Gene Farmer and staff writer Dora Jane Hamblin collaborated on writing First on the Moon: A Voyage with Neil Armstrong, Michael Collins and Edwin E. Aldrin, Jr., a book about the events of the Apollo 11 space mission and moon landing published in 1970. In-person taped interviews of the astronauts, astronauts' wives, and National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) staff before and after the mission were conducted by Hamblin and assistant editor Elizabeth "Betty" Dunn. Life Managing Editor Ralph Graves's files include a memorandum from Farmer discussing the issues around designing the dust jacket for and titling the "moon book," and that Life was not benefitting directly from the publication of the book although it did benefit from excerpts published in Life.
    Gene Farmer's files document the writing and publication of the book First on the Moon: A Voyage with Neil Armstrong, Michael Collins and Edwin E. Aldrin, Jr. and accompanying magazine articles on the first landing on the moon. While the files are Farmer's, there is extensive material from staff writer Dora Jane Hamblin who was lead on conducting interviews.
    Records include administrative files, book drafts, and research. Other titles found throughout the materials include Apollo! How the Moon was Won and To the Moon which may be working titles or the final titles for other books or articles.
    Organized into three subseries:
    IV.A.2.a. Administrative Files
    IV.A.2.b. Book Drafts
    IV.A.2.c. Research
    Related Materials
    Reviews and responses to the book are in Farmer's General Files.
    - Subsubseries IV.A.2.a. Administrative Files, 1969-1971, 2005; 230645; 0.5 Linear feet in 9 folders
      Administrative Files include correspondence and agreements with publisher Little, Brown; correspondence with the astronauts and National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) regarding the book outline and scheduling; and interoffice correspondence.
      - Apollo Movie Script (Apollo! Man and Space), 1969; 230646 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 1)
        A script for a motion picture by Arthur C. Clarke in collaboration with Francis Thompson Inc.
      - Audio Tapes Documentation, 1969-1971, 2005; 230647 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 2)
        Includes the memorandum from Hamblin describing and transferring the audio material to the Life Editorial offices, and the memorandum transferring the material to the Time Inc. Archives.
      - Books and Magazines, 1969; 230648 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence with Little Brown, 1969-1970; 230649 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 4)
      - Manuscript Typing, 1969; 230650 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 5)
      - Moon Book: Correspondence, 1969-1970; 230651 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 6-7)
        Besides correspondence to and from Farmer, records include transcripts of a Neil Armstrong interview and a conversation between Al Shepard, Hamblin, and Editorial Director Ralph Graves.
      - Moon Book: Memoranda and Edits, 1969-1970; 230660 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 8)
        Includes memoranda with edits and critiques, and copies of the typescript with corrections from the astronauts.
      - Moon Book: Outline: Discussion with Neil Armstrong [empty], 1969; 230652 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 9)
      - Photographs of Gene with Apollo 10 Crew, 1969; 230653 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 10)
    - Subsubseries IV.A.2.b. Book Drafts, 1969-1970; 230654; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
      Book drafts include several versions of the main body typescripts, some with corrections from astronauts, and drafts of front and back matter.
      - Acknowledgements, 1970; 230655 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 11)
      - Corrections for Galley Proofs, 1970; 230656 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 12)
      - Epilogue, 1970; 230657 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 13)
      - Footnotes, 1970; 230658 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 14)
      - Glossary, 1970; 230659 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 15)
        Includes a copy of Philco-Ford Corp Astronyms.
      - Photographs: Requests and Captions, 1969; 230661 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 16)
      - Quotations, 1970; 230662 (Offsite-box 2166, Folder 17)